# Ali Taee - Senior Front-end Developer

# **CONTACTS**

Ali.Taee.72@gmail.com
Linkedin
Stack overflow
Github

#### **SUMMARY**

As a Senior Front-end Developer with more than 4 years of experience in building responsive websites and web applications, I am always looking for a way to improve my work and team performance, from adding documents and unit tests to contributing my knowledge and giving feedback in code reviews. I enjoy Music, Photography, Novels, Travel and Technology.

### **SKILLS**

Jira, Scrum, Agile Development, HTML, CSS, CSS Processors, Responsive Design, JavaScript, TypeScript, JQuery, React, SPA, Gatsby, Next.Js, Redux, Socket.IO, REST API, E2E Testing, Unit Testing, Jest, Testing Library, Cypress, Parcel.Js, Webpack, Git.

# **EXPERIENCE**

<u>Snappfood</u>, Tehran, Iran — Senior Front-end Developer

February 2021 – Present

Snappfood with 2.5 million users per day is the largest online food ordering and grocery shopping platform in Iran.

- Work in a team of 10 people closely with designers, developers, QA engineers, scrum masters, and product managers using Scrum.
- Develop features and maintained the mobile applications using React, JavaScript, SCSS, and Redux-Saga.
- Develop features and maintained the desktop applications using React, TypeScript, Next.js, Storybook,
   Redux Toolkit, and styled-components.
- Onboard new developers and create a document for onboarding.
- Introduce Unit and E2E Testing with 5 technical presentations.

**Pishgam Vista,** Tehran, Iran — *Front-end Developer* 

December 2019 - June 2021

- Created front-end projects using JavaScript, React, Material-UI, Redux-thunk, Socket.IO, REST API.
- Reduced development time by creating common components.
- Collaborated with 8 other group members of designers, developers, product owners.
- Debugged 3 large legacy codes and refactored them for better performance and clean code.

- Implemented dashboards for our internal projects using React.
- Converted UI landing design into responsive web page.
- Launched a game campaign with a team of developers and designers within a tight deadline, using Vue.js.
- Released video gallery using HTML, CSS, Flexbox, and JavaScript, it increased average session duration by 5%.

**Arta Seo,** Esfahan, Iran — Front-end Developer / WordPress Developer

March 2018 - February 2019

- Communicated with customers to create their responsive websites based on their needs.
- Converted UI designs into WordPress responsive websites.
- Introduced WordPress plugin development to the company.
- Mentored a team of 10 interns to learn HTML, CSS, and WordPress.
- Reduced data entry time to 30% by optimizing the website panel.

<u>Asr-e Digital</u>, Esfahan, Iran — WordPress Developer / Website Manager

February 2014 – January 2017

- Proposed creating a blog to publish product reviews and news in Technology, this led to improving Alexa rank 2 times.
- Directed 3 translators to translate English content to Persian and content editing according to SEO .
- Customized a blog using WordPress for better user experience.

#### **EDUCATION**

Safahan, Isfahan — Associate's degree

# **LANGUAGES**

Persian (Native)

English (Advanced level)